ABU SUFIUN

Full Stack Developer: Laravel & React

* +880 1324724642, @ <u>abusufiun27@gmail.com</u>, Tongi, Gazipur, Pf https://sufiun27.github.io/AbuSufiun/, in https://www.linkedin.com/in/abu-sufiun, the https://github.com/sufiun27

SUMMARY

I am an expert in RESTful APIs, Laravel, and React, with a deep understanding of database management systems, including complex queries and database design. I excel in managing intricate and complex projects, as well as deploying projects from scratch. I possess in-depth knowledge of programming and problem-solving, and have experience as a Developer, Instructor, and Researcher. Additionally, I am proficient in AI and Machine Learning.

SKILLS

RESTful API, Laravel, React, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, MS-SQL, Oracle, My-SQL, OOP, PHP, JavaScript, C, AI, ML

EXPERIENCE

Mid-Level Laravel Developer

Hop Lun

May 2023 - Present, ST Tower, East Gazipura, Dhaka

- Top leading multinational R&D company based in Hong Kong. Since 1992.
- Implementing business and production analysis applications & ERP systems to increase company efficiency.
- Maintain server to deploy application and databases also Integrate different types of scanning device with ERP system.
- Conducted thorough testing and troubleshooting to ensure seamless functionality of applications and systems.
- Collaborated with multiple departments, including planning, production, merchandising, sewing, cutting, packing, ticketing, GGT, warehouse, HR, and sampling, to develop their software needs.

Lecturer - Department of Computer Science and Engineering

Daffodil International University

June 2022 - May 2023, Ashulia, Dhaka

- Take courses OOP, C programming, Database, Web Development, Application Development.
- Programming & Problem-Solving Lab-in-charge conducts different types of programming contest.
- Conducting classes and implementing Object-Based Education system also developer member of online- learning system.
- Published high impact full research papers and Advising students and conducting research.

PROJECTS

Project Management System

May 2024 - May 2024, Hop Lun Bangladesh

Technology uses React for the frontend and a Laravel RESTful API for the backend. Implemented user registration and login using Laravel Sanctum for secure API authentication.

- Enabled users to create projects, assign priority levels, and set status labels.
- Each project supports multiple tasks, which can be assigned to different users.
- The project list includes a summary of the total number of tasks and the number of completed tasks.
- Added search functionality for projects and tasks, with pagination and robust error handling for a fast and smooth user experience.

Style Analysis Efficient Swingline Planning

January 2024 - May 2024, Hop Lun Global

Technology uses Laravel, Bootstrap, JavaScript, MS-SQL, with optimal cash management to reduce API call and make faster the application.

- Similarity Analysis Between different swing styles and process also machine change over and generate auto planning for swing line.
- \bullet Increase Full production efficiency 30-45%, by make stable the efficiency target curve
- Optimal production line loading sequences and swing planning through style matching results in enhanced productivity and output.
- Optimize the allocation of resources, including machinery and manpower, by effectively planning production loads based on style matching matrices.

Multi Store Inventory Management System

May 2023 - July 2023, Hop Lun Bangladesh

Technology use Object-oriented PHP, Bootstrap framework, AJAX, and JavaScript for database use MS-Sql.

- That can handle multiple Database factory sub-stores inventory from one application.
- Different level authorization and authentication level
- Keep track buy and sell price and lot numbers and return policy
- generate finance report employee, department, stores and companies

Logistics Management Systems

September 2023 - December 2023, Hop Lun Bangladesh

Technology use with Laravel, MS-SQL, IIS, Bootstrap

- keep track of cost and available balance and shipment. To calculate factory cost and budget.
- maintain the commercial, audit, CAPEX, Banks TT Balance reports maintain huge amount data with yajra-datatable

EDUCATION

Bs.c. in Computer Science and Engineering (2017-2021)

Daffodil International University CGPA: 3.80 in the scale of 4

Higher Secondary School Certificate (2014-2016)

Major General Mahmudul Hasan Adarsha College CGPA: 4.92 in the scale of 5

Secondary School Certificate (2012-2014)

Dighulia Shahid Mizanur Rahman High School CGPA: 5.00 in the scale of 5

PUBLICATION

An AloT-based hydroponic system for crop recommendation and nutrient parameter monitorization Q1 Elsevier journal - Smart Agricultural Technology Volume 8, August 2024, 100472

Exploring the Relationship between Cardiac Disease and Patterns of 12-Lead Ecg Through Neural Network: A Comprehensive Review Heliyon Journal -

SSRN:http://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4464737

A Novel Approach of CNN Patterns Extraction for Bangla Handwriting to Bangla Braille Notation International Journal of Engineering Advanced Research, [S.l.], v. 3, n. 3, p. 1-15, dec. 2021. ISSN 2710-7167.

Automatic Bengali Number Plate Detection and Authentication using YOLO -V4 and YOLO-V5 International Conference on Computer and Information Technology (ICCIT) (pp. 1-6). IEEE.

REFERANCE

Dr. S.M. Aminul Haque

Associate Professor and Associate Head Department of Computer Science and Engineering, Daffodil International University, Bangladesh Cell Phone: 01847140129

Email: aminul.cse@daffodilvarsity.edu.bd

CERTIFICATION

Building Database Applications in PHP

University of Michigan • 2022

• Configure different Database connection with PHP

System Administration and IT

google Coursera • 2022

• Windows server and domain synchronization

Database Management Essentials

University of Colorado System • 2022

• Complex query and database design

TRANING

Business Analysis & Process Management (Jul 23 - Aug 23)

Hop Lun Apparel Limited - ST Tower, East Gazipura

• RND Company's business policies and leverage ERP modules to optimize production

Project Design and Management Course Outline (Jun 22 - Jul 22)

Daffodil International University - Ashulia, Dhaka

 Enhancing the Learning Curve in Project and Team Management

Teaching Apprentice Fellowship (Jan 20 - Aug 21)

Daffodil International University - Ashulia, Dhaka

• Mentorship & Leadership Development of students.

DECLARATION

I certify that the above information is true and accurate to the best of my knowledge. I acknowledge that providing false information may result in disqualification from any benefits.

Signature...